Name: Ibi

Email: ibi.olu@gmail.com, Mobile +44 (0) 7985209886.

Headline:

ISEB Certified Test Analyst with over 5years experience in Manual, Automation and Software Development Environments. Currently an upcoming developer with ability to create an ecommerce websites and webpages.

Deployed an operational project that increased company revenue, currently seeking a position where I can make a valuable contribution to utilise my exceptional skills abilities.

Technical Skills:

Test Tools: Selenium WebDriver, HP ALM, Jenkins, Cucumber, TestNG, Junit.

Front End: HTML, CSS, UI/UX, JavaScript and XML.

Language: Python (3.8.1), Java, C#, SQL.

Version Control: GitHub

Framework and libraries: Bootstrap, JQuery, PostmanAPI, Jira, Agile, Prince2, Wireframe.

Testing: Test Plan, Test Strategy, UAT, FAT, SAT and defect Reporting.

Dev TOOLS: Gitpod, Eclipse, AWS, google chrome Dev.

Employment History:

Employer: Freshwater Consulting Duration: Dec2019- May 2020

(A Start-up digital consulting services)

Role: Test Analyst and junior web developer (Web page improvements)

Responsibilities:

- Designed a Test plan and Test Strategy for the application under test.
- Build Test Framework from scratch.
- Manually tested the HTML AND CSS elements on the webpage.
- Manipulated the DOM elements in Dev tools to test some functionalities.
- Carried out End To End testing of the webpage.
- Improved the design of the landing page by incorporating JavaScript.
- Created goggle maps API's.
- Contributed to the improvement of pages User Experience.
- Designed and executed UAT test scripts on multiple Devices.

Employer: Hogarth (A digital creativity company)

Duration: Oct 2018-Dec 2019.

Role/Project: QA Test Eng. Intranet Frontend Testing.

Responsibilities:

Managed the Cucumber test framework in Selenium WebDriver.

- Worked with development team to improve Front End webpages.
- Used Jasmine framework to test the JavaScript code.
- Designed test cases in BDD to inspect Dom selector elements.
- Managed defects lifecycle in Jira.
- Tested multiple devices using chrome dev tools.
- Designed and Implemented Test Plan and Test Strategy for the test features.
- Developed and executed reusable automation test scripts in Selenium WebDriver.
- Automation and manual WEB API testing, google maps API, maps markers on multiple devices.
- Reviewed business requirements along with functional specification and coordinated UAT.
- Created test cases and regression test suites in Eclipse using TestNG.
- Carried API integration testing to ensure embedded links and external pages displayed.

Environment: Agile, Java, Scrum, Eclipse IDE, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, REST API, Jenkins, HTML, CSS, Cucumber, chropath, Agile and Atlassian Jira.

Employer: Simon Schuster (Online Digital)

Role /project: Test Analyst on mobile Apps, Web application and Backend.

Responsibilities:

- Defined test cases for **Front End** web elements.
- Managed task on TRELLO with dev team and business Analyst.
- Manually tested embedded videos, Iframe, Images, buttons and google Maps APIs.
- Tested API End Points Web pages using Postman Rest Client.
- Participated in all scrum ceremonies to ensure the SDLC and Test Strategy are followed.
- Verification, validation and testing through several iterations (Agile) in a Java development team.
- Reviewed software requirements, developed automated test plans and created automated tests scripts.
- Set up page object model Test frame framework from scratch in Selenium WebDriver.
- Developed regression test cases and coordinated User Acceptance test (UAT).
- Worked with release management to update version control using GIT.
- Managed test environments and produced weekly defects reports and collaborate on Slack.

Environment: Scrum, Java, AWS(IDE), DevOPs, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, REST API Testing, Postman, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, XPath, CSS, Safari, IOS, Android, Agile, Trello and GIT.

Employer: PhotoBox Duration: Feb 2016- March 2017
Test Analyst (Functional)

- Worked in agile environment along with graphic designer to gather user story, acceptance criteria
 for each functional requirements and produced test plan and strategy.
- Designed manual test cases based on functional requirements.
- Conducted End to End **UAT** with end users and secured sign off with managements.
- Managed defects and test summary reports in Jira along with developers.
- Used SQL functions to generate and retrieve data for database testing.
- Developed a UX process test cases along with User stories for a call to action feature.
- Application testing using Data driven test to allow for multiple data sets for various build.
- Created basic API tests, Usability, Smoke and sanity testing.
- Worked along with automation team to automate test scripts in Selenium WebDriver.
- Developed automated test scripts and test cases.

Environment: HP ALM, Selenium WebDriver, Excel, HTML, CSS, Windows 2010, Microsoft Dynamics, Android, IOS, Agile, Jira and Google Chrome, SDLC.

Employer: Anglian Ruskin Duration: Dec 2013- Dec 2015

Test Analyst (Manual testing of Front End VLE Website)

Carried out end to end testing including Exploratory testing on the VLE website, Responsibilities
are: Writing manual test cases, coordinated and produced UAT scripts, Mapped out sites to identify
URLs, HTML Meta tags, Web services testing, Retesting and regression testing of Bug fixes and
moved to QA Testbeds, run query on SQL databases for number generator, defect reporting .Worked
with release manager to create and maintain build verification (Smoke Testing) and Estimate testing
cycle.

Environments: SharePoint 2010, Advanced Excel, .net framework 3.5, Documentum, Citrix server, Ms Silver light and VB.net, WebTrends Enterprise Suite, Webbug for monitoring protocol, Project Server 2010 and SharePoint Server 2010.

Employer: Network Rail Duration: Jan 2007- Sept 2013

Test Analyst (Information Management)

Test analyst on multiple projects encompassing: Implementation pilot, UAT, FAT and SAT

Project1: A pension application interface system

Project2: Oracle supply chain management Synergy heavy Account payables/Receivables, order management and Inventory: Oracle Supply Chain is an end-to-end supply chain management system that further enables Network Rail to procure and manage material inventory.

Projects: Database decommissioning along with Iron Mountain.(Extensive use of SQL) to mirror data base copy.

Other Projects: SharePoint Migration, Documentum Software, ERP (Oracle Ebusiness) Implementation Programme, Oracle Hyperion implementation and Risk Asset register.

Environments- Oracle SQL, Bugzilla, SharePoint 2007, QTP, Quality Centre, Load Runner, Moss, XML, ASP.Net Oracle server 2008.

Achievement: Successful delivery of all projects and obtained business signoff for all testing cycles and supported 100% completion of migration.

EDUCATION

MS Computer Applications in Accounting.

ISEB Intermediate Software Testing.

Front End web development (in progress Code Institute)

Scrum Fundamental Cert/Prince 2 and Agile.

Static project (https://daat2.github.io/band-project/)

https://daat2.github.io/ccvitae/